brightest vitorio we're gonna talk about
how to do multiplication and division in
assembly alright so as you can see I've
set up the basic assembly file to print
a four-hour program so here I set up a
message saying the result of the
operation will be such-and-such and here
is the world code actually resigns and
I'm making reference to the printf
function from C calling library and of
course I'm making my main label
available to external vacations here I
create my stack frame and here I destroy
my stack frame okay so let's go ahead
and do multiplication real quick and say
we want to do 50 multiply by 3 which is
150 and so now how to do this instead of
assembly is to say we want to move a X
register to be 50 because the
multiplication instruction expects that
whatever you're going to be multiplying
by it's going to be held inside 50 and
it expects that the operand for
multiplication is going to be either a
register value or a memory location so
we're gonna use a memory location
because it's slightly faster to access
the CPU memory as opposed to actual
memory locations and so now we're gonna
say multiple x ECX now this means that
we're gonna say 3 the value stored
inside a X register because this has to
be a register value or a memory location
this multiplied by the value stored
inside of a extra ister so 50 times 3
and the result of the operation is going
to be stored inside out a X register
which means that 50 is going to be
erased and 150 is going to be put in its
place
so let's go ahead and call the printf
function
okay so over at our assembly line we're
gonna compile a program by saying nessam
net watt assembler produce and he had
e.l.f file using the input file ASM and
produce an output file called maltitol
and so a composite and then we're gonna
link it to the actual program to say GCC
make an output file called MLT and use
the input file that we generated from
here and so now we're gonna run the
program and there we go
so this is the result an F horse it's
150 so now let's do division okay so for
division it's slightly more different
yeah it's a little bit different because
an additional register is put in place
so general information let's cover
something real quick by saying looking
at the net wide assembler so this is the
file the website that I visited real
quick to get some information okay so
what it's saying is sorry for the number
we're gonna be dividing by you should be
held inside of the ax register such that
the higher end of the number is stored
inside of the DX register and the lower
end of the number students out of the ax
register and the results is stored again
in the ax register while the remainder
is stored inside of the edx register so
let's use this knowledge to perform
division so so basically we're still
wanting to do 50 divided by 3 but in
this case what we're gonna do is
move EDX with zero because really what
this is going to translate sue is saying
I wanted the EDX in combination words
the EAX register all of this value okay
it's going to be divided by three that's
basically what's going on so to satisfy
this rather odd combination is we want
to say move zero into DB X such that
this would be zero plus the number
stored inside of a X register so that's
it now remember of course the result is
still stored inside the ax register and
so let's go back to a command line and
recompile the program we generate the
file we link it and we run it mistake I
should change this to divide and save so
if we do this again
and of course we get 16 it's 16
it's 16 because we're doing integer
multiplication so the lower and so it
just returns the whole integer and so
yeah that's it for this tutorial
all right well that's going to do it for
this tutorial please as always leave a
comment below and rate and subscribe
thank you